

# Abdul Wazed Rifat

Tejgaon, Dhaka, Bangladesh 1 +88 0168-4855907

wazedrifat@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u> in

Portfolio (

GitHub 🌘

Diligent software engineer with more than 7 years of programming expertise and almost **3+ years of professional experience**. I enjoy coming up with the best possible solutions for any challenging situation through brainstorming. I took part in a lot of programming competitions to improve my problem-solving skills. Quick to pick up new frameworks and prefer effective teamwork where everybody can learn from each other. Excel at efficient time management and can deliver products on time.

## Work Experience

# **IQVIA**

May, 2023 - Present

## Software engineer 1

- Worked on an analytics systems where various dynamic analytics graphs were generated from DataMart.
- Provided Major contribution to Maintaining, bug fixing, and redesigning with improved performance for an application called feature designer. This is used to generate metadata cache, run data load for various database types.
- Quickly adapted and learned to use necessary technologies and expand knowledge base i.e. Fast API, .NET,
  Angular.
- Learned to use and debug and design various apps workflow via docker, Kubernetes, deployer scripts etc.
- Continuously upgraded and used best practices for all frameworks.
- Mentored, guided junior colleagues thorough solving any problems the proper way.
- Completed several releases while leading, mentoring and monitoring my team-mates.
- Handles Support for multiple types of databases i.e. snowflake, Firebolt, MSSQL, Oracle, Postgres, SQLite, mongo DB.
- Designed a ETL service to Generate SQLs to sync Postgres database with snowflake database.

# Relisource Technologies Ltd.

July, 2021 – April, 2023

#### Full stack software engineer

- Possess proficient knowledge of Medical Clinical Trial System (eCOA)
- Provided Major contribution to designing the optimized architecture for new features. Got appreciated many times for providing several optimization feedback and identifying crucial corner cases and more.
- Excelled as a proper code reviewer.
- Completed several releases while leading, mentoring and monitoring my team-mates.
- Utilizing nodes and edges, a schedule designer app with a dynamic graphical flow was created. made significant contributions to the frontend and backend architecture designs. used.NET for the backend microservice and angular 9 for the front end.
- Maintained & developed various features for an android ePro (Patient Reported Outcome) app using Xamarin Forms. Investigated & fixed various production bugs. Used AWS S3, firebase to store various logs and information. Used SQLite for the local database.
- Created a.NET & python console application to search database and AWS S3 logs for every production bug.
- Updated and bug-fixed a windows tablet application that site raters and physicians use to conduct forms.

## **Achievements**

<b>₽</b>	2nd in NEUB Junior IUPC 2017	December, 2017
<b>₽</b>	6th in AUB IUPC 2018	May, 2018
<b>₽</b>	13th in IUT 10th ICT Programming Contest	April, 2019
<b>₽</b>	18th in Technocracy 2019 by RUET, IUPC	July, 2019
₩.	23rd in MIST IUPC 2019	February, 2019
₩.	Participated in about 25+ Onsite Contests and hackathons	2017-2020

# Online Judges

Codeforces Wazed Rifat Max Rank: Expert (1623) Solved Problems: 500+

**CodeChef** Wazed Rifat Max Rank: 3 Star (1730)

vJudgeWazed RifatSolved Problems: 500+LightOJWazed RifatSolved Problems: 124

**LeetCode** Abdul Wazed Rifat

Solved Around 2000+ problems including all Online Judges

## **Education**

**Military Institute of Science and Technology** 

BSC in CSE

Govt. Science College

Science

Govt. Science College attached high school

Science

February, 2017 – February, 2021

**CGPA:** 3.61 out of 4.0 2015 – 2016

**GPA:** 5.0 out of 5.0 2013 – 2014

GPA: 5.0 out of 5.0

## **Skills**

### <u>Language</u>

- C#
- Python
- C++
- C
- TypeScript
- JavaScript
- SQL
- HTML

- .NET
- Fast API
- Flask
- Django
- Angular
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Git, Bitbucket
- Jira

### **Framework**

- WCF service
- Windows Forms
- Xamarin
- Entity Core
- Microsoft SQL
- Firebase
- AWS S3
- Azure blob storage

#### Skills

- Problem Solving
- Object Oriented Programming
- Design Pattern
- Algorithms
- Data Structures

# **Projects**

#### Schedule Designer | YouTube

Utilizing nodes and edges, a schedule designer app with a dynamic graphical flow was created. made significant contributions to the frontend and backend architecture designs. I Had to come up with many solutions with graph algorithms to meet various requirements. USA based client.

Technologies: .NET, Angular 9, blob storage, SQL Server